Thomas Corwin Mendenhall Personal Papers, 1910-1999
Smith College Archives
Thomas Corwin Mendenhall Personal Papers
1910-1999
Mendenhall, Thomas Corwin.
RG 32 UUID:b153d934-57ac-41b1-a245-d1c5a2b73bad
24 boxes (10 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
President, Smith College and professor, Yale University. Papers include correspondence, memorabilia, writings, hobbies, course materials, Rhodes Scholarship information, professional records, news clippings, portraits and photographs.
Thomas Corwin Mendenhall was born on June 14, 1910 in Chicago, IL to Charles E. Mendenhall, a physicist at the University of Wisconsin and Dorothy Reed Mendenhall, an 1895 graduate of Smith College and noted pediatrician.
Mendenhall received B.A. and Ph.D. degrees from Yale in 1932 and 1938, respectively, and held B.S. and B.Litt. degrees from Oxford University, where he was a Rhodes Scholar. Mendenhall was a history professor at Yale University and coach of the crew team (1937-1959). Six years later he began taking on administrative duties, first as assistant to the provost at Yale University (1943-1950), then as the master of Berkeley College, an undergraduate residential college at Yale University (1950-1959). During his time at Yale, Mendenhall assisted in the establishment of the Directed Studies Program, and, with other colleagues in the history department, initiated the "problem method" of teaching history, which emphasizes the analysis of source materials as the foundation for the development of historical generalizations.
Mendenhall was the sixth president of Smith College. He accepted the position in 1958, and began work in the fall of 1959. He remained at the college for 16 years, retiring in the spring of 1975. He guided Smith through a succession of changes that significantly altered the college's social environment and curriculum. Smith participation in intercollegiate athletic competition greatly increased on his watch. In addition, Mendenhall's interest in increasing the collaboration among Smith and its four neighboring institutions -- Amherst, Mount Holyoke and Hampshire colleges and the University of Massachusetts -- led to the founding of Five Colleges, Inc., of which he was president from its beginning until his retirement. Beyond the Smith community, Mendenhall served on the boards of a number of secondary schools and was actively involved with the Council for Basic Education. In 1962, Mendenhall helped found Catalyst, the national, nonprofit organization that seeks to advance women in business and the professions, and he later chaired its board.
Mendenhall retired to Martha's Vineyard in 1975 with his wife Cornelia Baker Mendenhall. He married Cornelia Baker in 1938. Cornelia was born in Englewood, NJ and graduated from Vassar with a degree in biology in 1935. She was a very caring and nurturing wife. During his retirement Mendenhall was active in the community life of Martha's Vineyard, serving on the boards of the Martha's Vineyard Hospital and several conservation groups and regularly sailing his Menemsha 24 sloop on Vineyard Sound. He researched and wrote books on the history of rowing in America (1975-1993). Crew and boating were two of Mendenhall's lifetime passions. He found rowing to be a great source of relief throughout his life. He captained the Balliol College crew while at Oxford, coached the Berkeley College crew while teaching at Yale, served as an informal coach for college rowers at Smith and wrote three books on the subject, including A Short History of American Rowing (1980).
Mendenhall was loved by many, and his death on July 18, 1998 at the age of 88 on Martha's Vineyard was mourned by all those whose lives he had touched. Surviving him are his two daughters Bethany Mendenhall and Cornelia Small, and two grandchildren. Cornelia Mendenhall died on October 17, 2002 on Martha's Vineyard.
The Mendenhall Papers include nearly 10 linear feet (24 document boxes) of material dating from 1910-1999. The papers include correspondence, writings, professional records, news clippings and photographs. For more specific information about the contents of the collection see the series descriptions and folder listing below.
Additional material in the Smith College Archives may be found in the papers of Mendenhall's mother, Dorothy Reed Mendenhall. They are housed in the Sophia Smith Collection. The presidential papers of Thomas Corwin Mendenhall may also prove useful.
This collection is organized into six series:
I. Biographical Material
II. Education
III. Personal Correspondence
IV. Professional Records
V. Writings and Speeches
VI. Photographs and Ephemera
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The collection is open to researchers according to the regulations of the College Archives. The letters of recomendation in Series IV are RESTRICTED.
History of the Collection
The Mendenhall papers were donated to the College Archives by Thomas and Cornelia Mendenhall in a number of accessions following his retirement as the president of Smith College in 1975.
Search Terms
Mendenhall, Thomas Corwin.; Smith College--Presidents.; Yale University--Administration.; Yale University--Faculty.; Historians--United States.; Comstock, Ada Louise.; Dunn, Mary Maples.; Fast, Louisa K.; Galbraith, V. H. (Vivian Hunter), 1889-; Hanks, Jane Richardson, 1908-; Hanks, Lucien M. (Lucien Mason), 1910-; Mendenhall, Charles E. (Charles Elwood), 1872-1935.; Mendenhall, Cornelia.; Mendenhall, Dorothy Reed, 1874-1964.
Additional Information
Related Material
Additional material in the Smith College Archives may be found in the papers of Mendenhall's mother, Dorothy Reed Mendenhall. They are housed in the Sophia Smith Collection. The presidential papers of Thomas Corwin Mendenhall may also prove useful.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, 2 document boxes/ 0.8 linear ft.
  The records in this series include news clippings, memorabilia, and correspondence. The bulk of the information relates to financial correspondence and rowing and sailing paraphernalia. There is also information about the Mendenhall family, travel memorabilia, and leisure activities.
  - General 1910-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1959-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bethany Land 1939-1952, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bethany Gilbert & Sullivan Society 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Childhood Miscellaneous undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Family
    - General 1936, 1940, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Children 1967, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Publication of "Mendenhall Family Affairs" Correspondence 1959-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Marriage 1937-1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Finances
    - General 1952-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Bank of Wisconsin 1949, 1956-1957, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Dorothy Reed Mendenhall's Estate 1950-1970, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Edith Allen Clark Estate 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - TCM Estate Plan 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Income Statements 1952-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Lists of Assets 1949-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Tax Returns 1936-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Bills & Receipts 1933-1943, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Rowing & Sailing 1930-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rowing & Sailing 1931-1940, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Travel
    - Passports 1925-1928 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Cruises 1929-1937, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Germany 1931-1938, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous 1935-1938, 1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Theatre Programs circa 1929-1936 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Theatre Programs 1930-1937, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous 1931, 1936, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- SERIES II. EDUCATION, 5 document boxes/ 2.1 linear ft.
  The files in this series are organized roughly chronologically by institution. Included are correspondence, papers, and memorabilia. Also included are sample examinations, crew team material, alumni material, and Rhodes scholarship information. Some oversized material is also included in a separate box (#5) near the end of the series.
  - Grade School 1919-1921 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Wisconsin High School 1921-1924 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Asheville School 1925, 1927, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ecole Alsacienne 1926 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Le Rosey-General 1927 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Le Rosey-Notebooks 1927 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Philips Academy 1927-1928 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Philips Academy-Correspondence 1931, 1934, 1937, 1950, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - College Entrance Exams 1925-1927 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Yale
    - General 1925-1938, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Examination Questions 1929-1938 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Graduate Work circa 1932-1937 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Track Team Memorabilia 1928-1932 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Undergraduate Autobiographical Essays undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Memorabilia 1927-1936 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Memorabilia 1937-1940, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, Folder 1 1927-1931 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - [OVERSIZE MATERIALS (Box 5)]
    - Miscellaneous Papers, Folder 2 1937 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Oxford
    - Crew 1934-1940, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Crew-Memorabilia 1933-1939 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Papers
      - "The Beckett Controversy" undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Bibliography for "Influence of the East on Roman Christian Act undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - "Death of James I - Natural or Unnatural?", by J. Roy Newton undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - "The Development of the Fury under Henry II" undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - "The Development of Parliament in the 14th Century" undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - "Foreign Period" undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - "Foreign Period" undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - "The Foreign Policy of Henry II" Mar 1931 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Frags undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - "Frederick as an Enlightened Despot" undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - "Gibbon's Decline & Fall of the Roman Empire" 1934 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - "How the Efforts of the Upper Landholding Classess to 1934 undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - "How far was Magna Carta a Baronial Reaction from 1934 undated undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - "In What Sense was England a Feudal Monarchy in the 1934 undated undated undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - "Johnson's Journey to the Western Isles" undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - "The Lancastrian Experiment" undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - "Locke, Hume, & Robertson undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - "Marivaux & Richardson" undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - "Military System of Edward I" undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - "Political Theory" undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - "Principles underlying the Foreign Policy of James I" undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - "Protectorate & Restoration" undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - "Richard II - as Treated by the Historians" undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - "Roman - Britain" undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - "The Significance of Domesday" undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - "Underlying Causes of the Baronial Revolt of 1268" undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Untitled, Period 1066-1272 Mar 1934 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - General 1933-1937 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Alumni Material 1940-1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Epaminonas, Philip & Alexander undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "Hellenistic Strategy" undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Rhodes Scholarship
      - General 1931-1938 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence 1931-1942 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Papers & Notes undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Receipts 1933-1937 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Memorabilia 1931-1934 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Memorabilia 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Memorabilia 1937-1939, 1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
- SERIES III. PERSONAL CORRESPONDENCE, 10 document boxes/ 4.2 linear ft.
  Mendenhall's personal correspondence comprises the bulk of his collection. The material is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, with a set of miscellaneous and unidentified items at the end. Some oversized material is also included in a separate box (# 16) at the end of the series.
  - Allison, John S. 1932-1936, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Baker, Mrs. G.D. [Cornelia's Mother] circa 1938 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Baker, Jaimie undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Balfour, Nancy 1934-1935, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Baltins, Nancy Solstad 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Barres, Dorothy & Hester [Hertic] 1931-1935, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bartholomew, Dwight 1970, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bauer, Nancy circa 1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bell, Edith 1933 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Benbow, Edna 1936, 1940, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Benson, Rita 1975-1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Bigelow, Sophia [Aunt Sophia, Mrs. Horace] 1936-1938 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Bill, Kenneth 1935-1937 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Bjorhus, Kathy 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Bodine, Betty & John 1933-1946, 1975-1985, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Bodine, Katherine W. 1935, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Bodine, Margaret 1938 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Bodine, Tom 1936 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Bonner, Susan Vaill 1976-1994 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Brewster, Mary 1935-1939 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Brown, Timothy 1935-1938 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Bush, George H. W. undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Child, Julia 1976 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Coffey, Keating 1928-1952, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Coffey, Titian & Eva 1930-1934 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Coffin, Fran Sue 1928-1933 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Corbin, Peter 1937-1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Costley-White, Cyril 1937, 1938, 1942, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Cousins, Hulda Fox [Friend of Louisa K. Fast] 1934-1938 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Cousol, Marguerite 1929-1934 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Cunningham, Hugh 1937-1942 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Davis, Catherine [Kate] 1931-1937, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Davis, Dick 1934-1935, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Dean, Janet 1934 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Deards, Anne 1933-1937, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - DeVane, Bill & Mabel 1948, 1950, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Dickinson, Alice 1973-1975, ca. 1987 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Dodge, Katherine & R.E. Neil 1926-1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Duckett, Eleanor 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Dumas, Hilda 1933-1940, 1949, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Dunham, Bill 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Dunlap, Cecile Bausman [CY] 1930-1935, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Dunn, Mary Maples 1990-1994 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - English, Jocelyn 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Faison, Sam L. 1933-1938 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Fast, Louisa K.
    - To CBM 1975, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - From CBM 1957-1965 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - From CBM 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - From CBM 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - From CBM 1971-1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - From CBM undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - To TCM 1932-1935, ca. 1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - From TCM 1966-1971, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Fates, Harold L. [Joe] 1935 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Flender, Mary [Molly] 1979, 1981, 1987, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Foord, Arch 1943-1950 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Fort, John Franklin [Frank, Buttercup] 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Friar, Mary 1936, 1937, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Galbraith, James & Jane 1936, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Galbraith, Matt 1989 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Gaunstatd, C. Harris 1934, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Gesell, Beatrice Chandler 1931-1935 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Gesell, Gerchard Alden & Masion [Gerry & Peggy] 1933-1937, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Gesell, Katherine Chandler [Tassy, Mrs. Joseph Walden] 1933-1937, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Gesell, Peggy [Peggy Pike] 1936 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Glover, Everett & Virginia [Ginnie] 1973-1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Gotwals, Vernon 1918-1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Greenleaf, Cynthia 1975-1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Griswold, A. Whitney & Mary 1950, 1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hanks, Jim 1932, 1938, 1958-1959, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hanks, June [Lucien] & Jane 1926-1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Hanks, June [Lucien] & Jane undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hart, Margaret M. 1931-1935 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Henning, Basil Duke 1936-1941, 1949-1964, 1980, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Hodgkinson, Laura 1936, 1977, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hoyt, Kity [Kit] 1980-1993 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hoyt, Nelly S. circa 1960, 1975, 1977, 1992-1994, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Jones, Llewellyn 1935-1936 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Kennedy, Jacqueline 1964 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Kenny, Anthony 1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Lamont, Helen [Aunt Helen] 1932-1935 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Langdale, Marion 1910 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Lascelles, John 1934-1937, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Leach, Mary Alice 1931-1934, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Lloyd, Frank & Betty 1935-1938, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Logue, Kathy 1979 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Lovett, Sid [Uncle Sid] undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Luederite, Clara 1934-1935, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - McGhee, George C. 1936-1937, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - McInerny, Anne [Pinkston] 1979-1981, 1995, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Mendell, C.W. 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Mendenhall, Bethany [Boo] 1952-1962, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Mendenhall, Charles E.
    - To TCM 1926-1935, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - From TCM 1926-1936 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - From Miscellaneous 1926-1932 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Mendenhall, Cornelia
    - From TCM 1938 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - From TCM [In England] Jun-Aug, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - From TCM [In England] Jun-Aug, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - To TCM 1950-1964 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Mendenhall, Dorothy Reed
    - From CBM circa 1937-1957 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - From TCM [From Switzerland] 1926-1927 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - From TCM [From Phillips Academy, Andover, MA] 1927-1928 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1928-1929, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1929-1930 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1930-1931 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1931-1932 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1932-1933 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1933-1934 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1935 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1936 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1937-1938 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1938 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - From TCM [On Sabbatical at Oxford] 1949-1950 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1955-1956 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1957 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - From TCM [From Yale] 1963-1964, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - From TCM Children 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - In Senior Drama Show with Florence M. Spalker: A Mid Summer Nights Dream 1895 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Condolences for the Death of DRM-Miscellaneous (A-L) 1964 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Condolences for the Death of DRM-Miscellaneous (M-Z) 1964 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Mendenhall, Mary 1954-1955, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Mendenhall, Nealy 1954-1955, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Monteivault, Ctesse de 1934 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Montgomery, Josephine 1933, 1934, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Montgomery, Mary Dudley 1932, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Moore, John D. & Mary 1933-1937, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Morgan, Constance 1967-1975 (Box 12)
    - To CBM 1967-1975 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - To TCM 1975-1995, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Moseley, Anna Burr 1932-1937 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Neff, Ruth & Eugene 1932-1937, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Notestein, Ada Comstock [Mrs. Wallace]
    - To CBM 1970 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - To TCM 1955-1968 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Notestein, Wallace 1933-1942, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Offner, Elliot 1980-1982 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Osborn, Bob 1965, 1970, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Overton, Mary [Aunt] 1933-1937 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Owen, David 1932-1936 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Paepke, Nitza 1934-1935, 1963, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Page-Gernon, Dorothy 1926-1934, undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Pargellis, Stanley & Elizabeth [Betty] 1932-1937 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Pollock, Herb 1936-1939, 1988, 1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Quidlen, Mary 1973-1977, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Quinn, Florence [Flo] 1975-1980 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Renwick, Ralph & Eliza 1933-1937, undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Rosenberry, Cicely 1918-1969, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Rosenberry, Marvin & Lois [Aunt Lois] 1934, 1937, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Rostow, Eugene V. 1950, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Rowland, Benjamin Allen [Al] 1932, 1933, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Schalk, Marshall 1980 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Sharp, Bestria & Frank C. 1935, 1938, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Sheriff, Bob 1935-1938 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Sherriff-MacGregor, M. Uma 1936-1938 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Simmons, Ruth 1994, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Smith, Caroline 1926-1931 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Standing, Mary 1932-1933 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Stella, Trudy 1975, 1976, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Stuurman, Don 1935-1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Sumner, Humphrey 1935-1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Tap, Hendrik 1931-1932 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Tener, Alexander 1932-1937, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Upton, Eleanor 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Vaill, George D. 1968-1975 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Van Dusen, Lewis 1933-1937, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Ward, Paul 1988-1994 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Watts, Ellen 1975, 1982, 1988-1990, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - White, Katherine [Mrs. E. B.] 1977 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Woodhall, Bertha 1934-1937, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Young, Francis 1930-1937, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Young, Karl 1935 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Zug, Jeanette & Charles 1929-1935, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - First Name Only
    - Barbara [Babs, B.] 1930-1931, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Bill 1932-1935, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - John 1931-1938, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Josh 1934, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Mac 1927-1928, 1935-1937 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Sheila 1933-1934 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Stephen 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Stewart [Stew] 1936-1938 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous A-Z circa 1920s (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous A-H circa 1930s (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous I-Z circa 1930s (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous A-Z circa 1940s (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous A-Z circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous A-Z circa 1960s (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous A-M circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous N-Z circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous A-Z circa 1980s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous A-Z circa 1990s (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous A-Z undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Family 1926-1969, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous No Names 1929-1938, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Holiday Cards A-Z, No Name 1933, 1936-1937, 1951, 1965, 1980, 1983, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - [OVERSIZE MATERIALS (Box 16)]
    - Brown, John 1934-1939, 1962, 1972-1995, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Galbraith, Vivian & Ena [wife] 1936-1940, 1952-1979, 1991, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Mendenhall, John & Sally 1926-1945 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Mendenhall, John & Sally 1950-1959 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Mendenhall, John & Sally 1960-1969 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Mendenhall, John & Sally 1970-1979 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Mendenhall, John & Sally 1980-1993, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Moore, Mary [Galbraith] & John D. 1933-1937, 1977-1994, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)